This is the foundation of spiritual life, spiritual aspiration—
这是灵性生活的基础，灵性渴望的基础
is recognising our own deficiencies;
认识到我们自己的不足
a candid assessment of our situation.
公正判断我们的处境
So, recognising our own imperfections,
认识到我们的不完美
[From Imperfection to Perfection]
从不完美到完美
but realising that this element within us
但我们也意识到
in the midst of so much imperfection,
在这么多不完美当中
that seeks perfection, is something very valuable, that tendency.
我们还在寻求着完美，这种追寻是很宝贵的
So even in the midst of so much imperfection
在诸多不完美当中
there’s this tendency to search for perfection,
我们还在追求着完美
the ideal, the Absolute.
追求着那个理想，那个绝对
And he [Guru Mahārāj] says, that tendency, it’s weak.
但Guru Maharaj说那种追求力其实很弱小
We’re told, jīva is an impoverished śakti,
经典里说，灵魂现在的能力很贫瘠
she needs to gain some wealth, some capital
她需要从一个高等的优秀奉献者那里
from a superior servitor, āśrayāḥ-vigraha, chit-śakti—
获得一些资本财富
He said, so this tendency to seek perfection
所以他说这体悟完美的能力不够
is very weak, otherwise we would have it by now,
不然我们早就达成了
we would have attained it.
现在就拥有了完美
But, he said, so that’s the nature of the finite
他也说，受局限的有限的个体
is to be subjected to imperfection.
本性上是不完美的
But that points to the need— we have to address that,
因此，我们才需要解决这个需求
to fulfil that, it’s beyond ourselves, is outside of ourselves.
而达成这个愿望是超越我们自身能力的
He said, so that makes room for the guru, or the guide,
因此，就有必要寻求古茹导师的指引
which is the functioning principle of Divinity
这就是神性在这个世界上揭示自己时的方法
And here, Guru Mahārāj says,
Guru Maharaj也说
“And the Perfect, by dint of being the perfect,
完美，意味着对完美存在来说
the means for revealing Himself
他揭示自己是件很简单容易的事情
It’s the Infinite who can make Itself known to the finite,”
无限能够将自己展示给有限存在
as Guru Mahārāj said, “Otherwise He is not Infinite”.
就像Guru Maharaj说的，“不然他就不是无限的了”
And therein lies our prospect,
这照亮了我们的前景
and that’s the beauty, mysterious charm
这就是奎师那觉知的美和神奇的迷人之处
[It] is coming in connection with the Infinite,
与无限连接起来
the Supreme Lord, the Supreme Absolute Truth,
与至尊主，至尊绝对真理相连
Reality the Beautiful,
那个美丽的本真连接
by connecting with His agent,
通过与他的代理人相连
divine agency, Śrī Guru, the divine guide.
神圣的代理古茹给予的圣贤指导
Because, and Guru Mahārāj deals with this also, and he said,
Guru Maharaj也通常这么说
“One might think, ‘Well, you can get all this internally,
“有人认为，这些你内在都可以获得
what is the need of help outside yourself?’”
为何还需要外界的帮助？”
He said, but that voice within us is often unreliable;
但我们内在的声音并不总是可靠的
we cannot discern the voice of God,
我们不能辨别神的声音
the voice of Divinity,
哪个是来自神性的声音
from our own speculative imaginings
哪个是我们的想象猜测
or wishful thinking, or selective remembrance.
哪个是愿望或者选择性的记忆
So, he said, very mercifully Kṛṣṇa comes before us
因此奎师那仁慈地来到我们面前
as the guide, or the guru, to guide us
让古茹来指引我们
from the world of imperfection towards the world of perfection,
从不完美走向完美世界
by activating our serving capacity.
通过激活我们服务的能力来实现